SHIKHAR KAPOOR () Featured

OCJP Senior RPA Developer seeking roles in Software Development, Robotic Process Automation, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, Blue Prism, UiPath, Eclipse, MS SQL, Trust Portal



Current Designation: RPA Developer Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Zyclyx consulting Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Location: Pune Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Information Technology]

Pref. Location: Chennai, Gurgaon, Pune

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Senior RPA Developer, Software Developer, Software Development, Robotic Process Automation, Application

 $Programming, Application\ Maintenance, Project\ Management, Requirement\ Analysis, Solution\ Architecture, Blue$

Prism, UiPath, Eclipse, MS SQL, Trust Portal

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 19-Jan-21 Last Modified: 19-Jan-21

Summary

3+ years of experience in Robotic Process Automation.

Automated 15+ end to end Processes using Blue prism and UI path tool.

Onsite experience of 1 year, working directly with one of the renowned Bank.

Worked within project planning constraints, presented business case to client for various processes, identified project risks and issues to deliver process accordingly.

Provided automated solutions for Banking, Insurance and Telecom sector.

Possess strong communication, interpersonal and problem-solving skills, worked on various roles like RPA developer, code reviewer. Technical Analyst etc.

Good analytical skill and ability to adapt to new environment & technology quickly and efficiently.

Work Experience

Zyclyx consulting as RPA Developer Jan 2020 to Till Date

Zyclyx as Senior RPA Developer Jan 2020 to Nov 2020

Worked on two clearance process from initial process analysis to end to end process automation for collection's department, saved 3 FTE's cost for the client. Developed the process using Blue prism and currently working on integrating the process with the Trust portal for direct interaction of User with Robot.

Zyclyx [Senior RPA Developer]

II. July-Aug2020 (Card Department Automation)

Automated process for Card operations department of one the leading bank of Saudi Arabia, the basic functionality of the process is to settle card related monetary issues of the customer and if needed transferring the pending/difference amount to Customer and sending the closure details back via SMS.

III. May-June2020 (Compliance Department)

Automated process for compliance department of the Bank to Block and unblock accounts of the customer in Bank by taking details of legal blocked and unblocked list from Monetary authority and comparing the details with bank's internal

data and performing the required Operation.

IV. April-May2020 (Personal Loan Process Automation)

Automated processes for Loan department of Bank where the basic functionality is to approve/Reject/Reassign the loan of existing customers of bank by verifying and matching data provided and also calculate the eligibility limit of the loan based on more than fifty verification checks.

V. Feb-March 2020(Settlement of Corporate Loans)

Automated process for Backend operations team of the bank where the basic functionality is to settle the corporate loan of the bank partially or fully depending upon different scenarios and sending the final report and documents of the settlement to operations team.

VI. Jan-Feb 2020 (Treasury)

Automated process for Treasury department of the Bank it checks for balance in all the foreign account of the bank and provide amount/currency that needs to be added to that particular account to maintain the min balance.

Zyclyx [RPA Developer]

This process belongs to finance department of a renowned telecom company and is focused on validating and processing vouchers received as input to make them ready for final approvals before paying off.. The finance team of process owner and SMEs have been fully satisfied with the process as it served the projected purpose completely. Robot processes them through multiple steps in web application to make them ready for approval.

Capgemini as Associate Consultant

Jun 2017 to Dec 2019

VII. September - Dec 2019

Basic functionality of this project was to automate the L1 team tasks. UI Path tool was used in order to automate HPESM web application. All the incidents that come into the application was handled and processed by BOTS built up on the UiPath.

Capgemini [Associate Consultant]

VIII. June -Nov 2018

Developed Access renewal tool for Account to check for access Renewal dates for all employees from the list and send mail as a Reminder to all the employees keeping their n+1 in CC whose Renewal date is within next 30 days.

Capgemini [Senior Software Engineer]

IX. Nov -March 2018

Capgemini [Senior Software Engineer] April 2018- Feb 2019 Developed end to end regression testing suite for a BPM Customer product application, Test suite needs to run after maintenance time on every Sunday to check for each functionality/service working properly and correct data is published at the user side. The product saves a lot of time and billing for the client.

Capgemini [Software Engineer]

X. June 2017-Oct 2017

Capgemini [Senior Software Engineer] Nov 2017 - April 2018 Customer requests for account closure through an email or through the web portal. So Bot interacts with web portal & emails, gathers the relevant information and processes to the further stages and once approvals are given then bank will close their relationship with the customers.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Information Technology) from GL Bajaj Institute of Technology & Management, Greater Noida in 2016

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Blue Prism	
UiPath, Eclipse	
MS SQL	

Languages Known

 $1/22/2021 \hspace{1.5cm} https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=29dccfe632304b252580ebd803d421f858590e0018140a110011415958... \\$

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time